<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="hello">Physics Cheater</string>
    <string name="app_name">Physics Cheater</string>
    <string name="formula_screen_name">Formulae List</string>
    <string-array name="countries_array">
        <item>Mechanics</item>
        <item>Rotational Motion</item>
        <item>Work, Energy, Power</item>
        <item>Electric Current</item>
        <item>Electrostatics</item>
        <item>Fluids</item>
        <item>Heat and Thermodynamics</item>
        <item>Impulse, Momentum</item>
        <item>Magnetism</item>
        <item>Optics</item>
        <item>Gravitation</item>
        <item>Electromagnetic Waves</item>
        <item>Important Constants</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="Mechanics"><u>Newton\'s second law</u>\nF = m.a\nwhere F = net force applied\nm = mass\na = acceleration\n\n\n<u>Friction Force</u>\nF<sub>friction</sub> &lt;= µF<sub>norm</sub>\nwhere µ is the coefficient of friction and it depends on type of material.\nF<sub>norm</sub> is the reaction of the surface to the object because of its weight. Generally F<sub>norm</sub> = m.g\n\n<u>Relative Motion</u>\nV<sub>relative</sub>=V<sub>object</sub> - V<sub>observer</sub>\n\n<u>Horizontal Motion</u>\nX=V.t\nwhere X = distance\n\n<u>Vertical Motion</u>\nV = V<sub>i</sub>t + gt\nwhere g = acceleration due to gravity -9.8m/s<sup>2</sup>\nX = V<sub>i</sub>t + 1/2g.t<sup>2</sup>\n</string>
    <string name="WPE"><u>Work</u>\nUnit of Work is kg.m<sup>2</sup>/s<sup>2</sup>, also known as <i>joule</i>.\n1 joule = 1N.1m\nWork = Force.Distance\n\n<u>Power</u>\nPower = Work/time interval.\nUnit of power is <i>watt</i>.\n1 joule/s = 1 watt.\n\n<u>Energy</u>\nMechanical Energy = Potential Energy + Kinetic Energy.\n\n<u>Potential Energy</u>\nE<sub>p</sub> = m.g.h\nwhere h = height.\nIn case of a spring. E<sub>p</sub> = 1/2.k.x<sup>2</sup>\nwhere k is the spring constant.\n\n<u>Kinetic Energy</u>\nE<sub>K</sub>=1/2m.v<sup>2</sup></string>
    <string name="IM"><u>Momentum</u>\nMomentum = Mass * Velocity\n\n<u>Impulse</u>\nImpulse = Force. Time interval\nImpulse = change in momentum\n\n<u>Conservation of Momentum</u>\nP<sub>initial</sub>=P<sub>final</sub>\nm<sub>1</sub>v<sub>1</sub> = m<sub>2</sub>v<sub>2</sub></string>
    <string name="RM"><u>Tangential Speed(Linear Speed)</u>\nV<sub>A</sub> = 2πr/T\nwhere V<sub>A</sub> is the tangential speed and T is the time period for one revolution.\n\n<u>Frequency</u>\nFrequency is the inverse of the time period.\nf = 1/T\nso, V<sub>A</sub> = 2πrf\n\n<u>Angular Speed</u>\nω = 2π/T = 2πf\n\n<u>Angular Acceleration</u>\nα<sub>centripetal</sub> = -4π<sup>2</sup>r/T<sup>2</sup>\nα<sub>centripetal</sub> = -ω<sup>2</sup>r = V<sub>A</sub><sup>2</sup>/r\n\n<u>Centripetal Force</u>\nF<sub>c</sub> = -m4π<sup>2</sup>r/T<sup>2</sup> = mV<sub>A</sub><sup>2</sup>/r\n\n<u>Torque</u>\nτ = Applied Force * Distance * sinӨ\nwhere Distance is the shortest distance between the point of application of force and the fixed axis; Ө is the angle of application of force.</string>
    <string name="OP"><u>Reflection of light</u>angle of incident ray = angle of reflection\nθ<sub>1</sub> = θ<sub>2</sub>\n\n<u>Moving plane mirror</u>\nIf the mirror moves with a velocity of V, then image of the object moves with the velocity of 2V.\nIf the object moves with a velocity V then image also moves with V but in the opposite direction.\n\n<u>Mirror equations of curved mirrors</u>\n1/f = 1/D<sub>o</sub> + 1/D<sub>i</sub>\n\n<u>Refractive Index</u>\nn<sub>a</sub> = Speed of light in vacuum/speed of light in a medium = c/V<sub>a</sub>\n\n<u>Snell\'s Law</u>\nn<sub>1</sub>.Sinθ<sub>1</sub> = n<sub>2</sub>.Sinθ<sub>2</sub>\nn<sub>1</sub>/n<sub>2</sub> = v<sub>1</sub>/v<sub>2</sub>\nwhere, θ<sub>1</sub> angle of the incident ray and θ<sub>2</sub> is the angle of the refracted ray, n<sub>1</sub>, n<sub>2</sub> are refractive indices of the mediums and v<sub>1</sub> and v<sub>2</sub> are velocity of light in the mediums.\n\n<u>Critical angle and total reflection</u>\nsin θ<sub>c</sub> = n<sub>1</sub>/n<sub>2</sub>\nRays coming with an angle larger than θ<sub>c</sub> make total reflection.\n\n<u>Apparent depth and Real depth</u>\nD<sub>a</sub> = D<sub>r</sub> * n<sub>observer</sub>/n<sub>object</sub>\nwhere, D<sub>a</sub> is the apparent depth, D<sub>r</sub> = real depth, n<sub>observer</sub> = refractive index of the medium of the observer and n<sub>object</sub> is the refractive index of the medium of the object</string>
    <string name="TD"><u>Temperature</u>\nC/100 = (F-32)/180 = (K-273)/100\n\n<u>Heat</u>\nQ = m.c.∆T\nwhere c Q is the heat transfered, m is the mass of the body, c is the specific heat capacity and ∆T is the change in temperature\n\n<u>Heat transfer</u>\nQ<sub>gained</sub>=Q<sub>lost</sub>\nm<sub>1</sub>c<sub>1</sub>∆T<sub>1</sub>=m<sub>2</sub>c<sub>2</sub>∆T<sub>2</sub>\n\n<u>Thermal expansion</u>\n∆V=V<sub>0</sub>.α. ∆T\nwhere ∆V is the change in the volume, α is the coefficient of thermal expansion and ∆T is the change in temperature of the matter\n\n<u>Linear expansion</u>\n∆L=L<sub>0</sub>.α. ∆T\n\n<u>Area expansion</u>\n∆S=S<sub>0</sub>.2α. ∆T\n\n<u>Volume expansion</u>\n∆V=V<sub>0</sub>.3α. ∆T</string>
    <string name="ES"><u>Coulumb\'s Law</u>\nF = k(q<sub>1</sub>q<sub>2</sub>)/d<sup>2</sup>\nwhere q<sub>1</sub> is the amount of charge on object 1, q<sub>2</sub> is the amount of charge on object 2, k is te proportionality constant and d is the distance between two objects\n\n<u>Electric Field</u>\nE = F/q = kq/r<sup>2</sup>\nElectric field is a vector quantity and it decreases with the increasing distance. k = 9 X 10<sup>9</sup>N.m<sup>2</sup>/C<sup>2</sup>\n\n<u>Force acting on a charged particle in Electric field</u>\nE = F/q\nwhere F is the force acting on the particle with charge q in an electric field E.If q is positive then F=+E.q and directions of Force and Electric Field are same. If q is negative then F =-E.q and directions of Force and Electric Field are opposite.\n\n<u>Electric Potential Energy</u>\nElectric potential energy = k (q<sub>1</sub>.q<sub>2</sub>)/d\n\n<u>Electric potential</u>\nV = k.q/d\nV is a scalar quantity. If q is negative then V becomes negative, or if q is positive then V becomes positive. Surfaces having equal potentials are called equipotential surfaces.\n\n<u>Capacitance</u>\nC = Q/V\nwhere C is the capacitance of the conductor, Q is the amount of charge gained and V is the potential gained.\n\n<u>Capacitors</u>\nC = Ε.A/d\n\n<u>Capacitors in Parallel</u>\nQ<sub>1</sub> = C<sub>1</sub>V\nQ<sub>2</sub> = C<sub>2</sub>V\nC<sub>eq</sub> = C<sub>1</sub>+C<sub>2</sub>C<sub>3</sub>\n\n<u>Capacitors in Series</u>\nC<sub>1</sub>V<sub>1</sub> = Q\nC<sub>2</sub>V<sub>2</sub> = Q\n1/C<sub>eq</sub> = 1/C<sub>1</sub> + 1/C<sub>2</sub></string>
    <string name="EC"><u>Electric Current</u>\nI = ∆Q/∆t\nwhere I is the current, Q is the charge and t is the time. The unit of electric current is Coulomb per second or Ampere (A).\n\n<u>Resistance</u>\nR=ρl/A\nwhere ρ is the resistivity, l is the length and A is the area of the material\n\n<u>Ohm\'s Law </u>\nV<sub>1</sub>/I<sub>1</sub> = constant = R\n\n<u>Resistors in series</u>\ni = i<sub>1</sub> = i<sub>2</sub> = i<sub>3</sub>\nV = V<sub>1</sub> + V<sub>2</sub> + V<sub>3</sub>\nR<sub>eq</sub> = R<sub>1</sub> + R<sub>2</sub> + R<sub>3</sub>\n\n<u>Resistors in parallel</u>\ni = i<sub>1</sub> + i<sub>2</sub> + i<sub>3</sub>\nV = V<sub>1</sub> = V<sub>2</sub> = V<sub>3</sub>\n1/R<sub>eq</sub> = 1/R<sub>1</sub> + 1/R<sub>2</sub> + 1/R<sub>3</sub>\n\n<u>Batteries</u>\nEMF is the energy given by the battery to the unit charge when it passes from one end to the other end of the battery. We can say that, if the EMF of the closed circuit is known then EMF is directly proportional to the charge in the circuit.\nW=ε.Q where Q=i.t\nW=ε.i.t\n\n<u>Batteries in series</u>\nε<sub>eq</sub>=ε<sub>1</sub>+ε<sub>2</sub>+ε<sub>3</sub>+...+ε<sub>n</sub>\n\n<u>Batteries in parallel</u>\nε<sub>eq</sub>=ε<sub>1</sub>=ε<sub>2</sub>=ε\n1/r<sub>eq</sub> = 1/r<sub>1</sub> + 1/r<sub>2</sub>...+ 1/r<sub>n</sub>\n\n<u>Energy</u>\nE=i<sup>2</sup>.R.t=V<sup>2</sup>/R.t\n\n<u>Electric power</u>\nP = V.i\nP = i<sup>2</sup>.R = V<sup>2</sup>/R</string>
    <string name="MG"><u>Coulomb\’s Law for Magnetism</u>\nF = k m<sub>1</sub>.m<sub>2</sub>/d<sup>2</sup>\nF<sub>1</sub> = -F<sub>2</sub>\nwhere k is the constact, m<sub>1</sub> and m<sub>2</sub> are the magnetic intensities of the poles and d is the distance between them.\n\n<u>Magnetic field</u>\nMagnetic field is a vector quantity and showed with the letter B. Unit of B is Tesla. When we calculate magnetic field of a magnet we assume that there is a 1 unit of m at the point we want to find. We find the magnetic field with following formula:\nB = F/m\n\n<u>Magnetic Flux</u>\nWe show magnetic flux with the Greek letter; Ф. We find it with following formula:\nФ=B.A.cosӨ\nWhere Ф is the magnetic flux and unit of Ф is Weber (Wb), B is the magnetic field and unit of B is Tesla, A is the area of the surface and unit of A is m<sub>2</sub>.\n\n<u>Magnetic Field around a Wire</u>\nB=2k.i/d\n\n<u>Magnetic Field around a Circular Wire</u>\nB = 2πk.i/r\n\n<u>Magnetic Field around a Solenoid</u>\nB = 4πk i.N/l\nwhere i is the current, N is the number of loops and l is the length of the solenoid.\n\n<u>Force Acting on Moving Particle and Current Carrying Wire</u>\nF=B.i.l.sinß\n\n<u>Force Acting on Charged Particle</u>\nIf the particle has charge q, velocity v and it is placed in a magnetic field having strength B force acting on this particle and ß is the agle between the velocity and magnetic field is found with following formula\nF=q.v.B.sinß\n\n<u>Forces of Currents Carrying Wires on Each Other</u>\nF = B<sub>1</sub>.i<sub>2</sub>l = 2.k.(i<sub>1</sub>.i<sub>2</sub>.l)/d\nwhere l is the length of the wires, d is the distance between them.</string>
    <string name="G"><u>Kepler\'s Laws</u>\nFollowing are the three Kepler\'s laws\n1.The orbit of each planet is an ellipse which has the Sun at one of its foci.\n2.Each planet moves in such a way that the (imaginary) line joining it to the Sun sweeps out equal areas in equal times.\n3.The squares of the periods of revolution of the planets about the Sun are proportional to the cubes of their mean distances from it.\n\n<u>Newton\'s law of universal gravitation</u>\nF = G.m1.m2/r<sup>2</sup>\nwhere F is the force due to gravity, g the acceleration due to gravity, G the Universal Gravitational Constant (6.67x10<sup>-11</sup> N.m<sup>2</sup>\/kg<sup>2</sup>), m the mass and r the distance between two objects.\n\n<u>Acceleration due to gravity outside the Earth</u>\ng\' = (r<sub>e</sub><sup>2</sup>/r<sup>2</sup>).g\nwhere g\' is the acceleration due to gravity at a radius r outside the earth in terms of the Earth\'s radius (r<sub>e</sub>) and the acceleration due to gravity at the Earth\'s surface g.\n\n<u>Acceleration due to gravity inside the Earth</u>\ng\' = (r/r<sub>e</sub>)g\nwhere r represent the radius of the point inside the earth.\n\nNote: In both the above formulas, as expected, g\' becomes equal to g when r = r<sub>e</sub>.</string>
    <string name="C"><u>Constants and conversion factors</u>\n\n1 unified atomic mass unit : 1u = 1.66 X 10<sup>-27</sup>kg or 931 MeV/c<sup>2</sup>\n\nProton mass : m<sub>p</sub> = 1.67 X 10<sup>-27</sup> Kg\n\nNeutron mass : m<sub>n</sub> = 1.67 X 10<sup>-27</sup> Kg\n\nElectron mass : m<sub>e</sub> = 9.11 X 10<sup>-31</sup> Kg\n\nMagnitude of electronic charge : e = 1.60 X 10<sup>-19</sup> C\n\nAvagadro\'s number : N<sub>0</sub> = 6.02 X 10<sup>23</sup> mol<sub>-1</sub>\n\nUniversal gas constant : R = 8.31 J/(mol.K)\n\nBoltzman\'s constant k<sub>B</sub> = 1.38 X 10<sup>-23</sup> J/K\n\nSpeed of light : c = 3.00 X 10<sup>8</sup> m/s\n\nPlanck\'s constant : h = 6.63 X 10<sup>-34</sup> J.s\n\nVacuum permittivity : ε<sub>0</sub> = 8.85 X 10<sup>-12</sup> C<sup>2</sup>/N.m<sup>2</sup>\n\nCoulomb\'s law constant : 1/(4πε<sub>0</sub>) = 9.0 X 10ε<sup>9</sup> N.m<sup>2</sup>/C<sup>2</sup>\n\nVacuum pemeability : α<sub>0</sub> = 4π X 10<sup>-7</sup> T.m/A\n\nMagnetic constant k<sup>\'</sup> = α/4π = 10<sup>-7</sup> T.m/A\n\nUniversal gravitation constant : G = 6.67x10<sup>-11</sup> N.(m\kg)<sup>2</sup>\n\nAcceleration due to gravity : g = 9.8 m/s<sup>2</sup>\n\n1 atmosphere pressure : 1 atm = 1 X 10<sup>5</sup> N/m<sup>2</sup> = 1 X 10<sup>5</sup> Pa\n\n1 electron volt : 1eV = 1.60 X 10<sup>-19</sup> J.</string>
    <string name="EMW"><u>Maxwell\'s Equations</u>\nMaxwell\’s four equations describe the electric and magnetic fields arising from varying distributions of electric charges and currents, and how those fields change in time.\nHere are the equations:\n1. Gauss\' Law for electric fields:\n∫E<sup>-</sup>.dA<sup>-</sup> = q/ε<sub>0</sub>\nThe integral of the outgoing electric field over an area enclosing a volume equals the total charge inside, in appropriate units.\n\n2. The corresponding formula for magnetic fields:\n∫B<sup>-</sup>. dA<sup>-</sup> = 0\nNo magnetic charge exists: no “monopoles”.\n\n3. Faraday\’s Law of Magnetic Induction:\n∮E<sup>-</sup>. dl = -d/dt (∫B<sup>-</sup>.dA<sup>-</sup>)\nThe first term is integrated round a closed line, usually a wire, and gives the total voltage change around the circuit, which is generated by a varying magnetic field threading through the circuit.\n\n4. Ampere\’s Law plus Maxwell\’s displacement current:\n∮B<sup>-</sup>. dl = µ<sub>0</sub>(I + d/dt(ε<sub>0</sub> (∫E<sup>-</sup>.dA<sup>-</sup>)))\nThis gives the total magnetic force around a circuit in terms of the current through the circuit, plus any varying electric field through the circuit (that\’s the “displacement current”).\n\n<u>Electromagnetic Wave Equation</u>\nThe wave equation for a plane electric wave traveling in the x direction in space is:\nd<sup>2</sup>E/dx<sup>2</sup> = 1/c<sup>2</sup>. d<sup>2</sup>E/dt<sup>2</sup>\nwith the same form applying to the magnetic field wave in a plane perpendicular the electric field. Both the electric field and the magnetic field are perpendicular to the direction of travel x. The symbol c represents the speed of light or other electromagnetic waves.The wave equation for electromagnetic waves arises from Maxwell\'s equations. The form of a plane wave solution for the electric field is:\nE = E<sub>m</sub>sin(kx - ωt)\nand that for magnetic field is:\nB = B<sub>m</sub>sin(kx - ωt)\nTo be consistent with Maxwell\'s equations, these solutions must be related by\nE<sub>m</sub>/B<sub>m</sub> = c\nThe magnetic field B is perpendicular to the electric field E in the orientation where the vector product E x B is in the direction of the propagation of the wave.\n\n<u>Energy in Electromagnetic Waves</u>\nElectromagnetic waves carry energy as they travel through empty space. There is an energy density associated with both the electric and magnetic fields. The rate of energy transport per unit area is described by the vector:\nS<sup>-</sup> = 1/µ<sub>0</sub>E<sup>-</sup>.x.B<sup>-</sup>\nwhich is called the Poynting vector. This expression is a vector product, and since the magnetic field is perpendicular to the electric field, the magnitude can be written:\nS = (1/µ<sub>0</sub>)EB\nThe rate of energy transport S is perpendicular to both E and B and in the direction of propagation of the wave.\nA condition of the wave solution for a plane wave is B<sub>m</sub> = E<sub>m</sub>/c so that the average intensity for a plane wave can be written:\nS = (1/cµ<sub>0</sub>)E<sub>m</sub><sup>2</sup>sin<sup>2</sup>(kx - ωt) = (1/cµ<sub>0</sub>). (E<sub>m</sub><sup>2</sup>/2)\nThis makes use of the fact that the average of the square of a sinusoidal function over a whole number of periods is just 1/2.</string>
    <string name="F"><u>Pressure</u>\nAverage pressure P<sub>av</sub> is defined as the normal force acting per unit area\nP<sub>av</sub> = F/A\n\n<u>Density</u>\nρ = m/V\nThe dimensions of density are [ML–3]. Its SI unit is kg m<sup>–3</sup>.\n\n<u>Pascal\'s Law</u>\nThe pressure in a fluid at rest is the same at all points if they are at the same height.\nThe pressure P, at depth below the surface of a liquid open to the atmosphere is greater than atmospheric pressure by an amount ρgh\nP = P<sub>a</sub> + ρgh\n\n<u>Archimedes\' Principle</u>\nWhen a body is wholly or partially immersed in a fluid at rest, the fluid exerts pressure on the surface of the body in contact with the fluid. The pressure is greater on lower surfaces of the body than on the upper surfaces as pressure in a fluid increases with depth. The resultant of all the forces is an upward force called buoyant force.\n\n<u>Streamline flow</u>\nThe mass of liquid flowing out equals the mass flowing in, holds in all cases. Therefore\nρ<sub>P</sub>A<sub>P</sub>v<sub>P</sub> = ρ<sub>Q</sub>A<sub>Q</sub>v<sub>Q</sub>\nfor an incompressible fluid\nA<sub>P</sub>v<sub>P</sub> = A<sub>Q</sub>v<sub>Q</sub>\nwhich is called the equation of continuity\n\n<u>Bernoulli\’s equation</u>\nAs we move along a streamline the sum of the pressure (P), the kinetic energy per unit volume (v<sup>2</sup>/2) and the potential energy per unit volume (ρgh) remains a constant\n P + v<sup>2</sup>/2 + ρgh = constant\n\n<u>Torricelli\’s law</u>\nThe speed of efflux, v<sub>1</sub>, from the side of the container is given by the application of Bernoulli\’s equation. If the container is open at the top to the atmosphere then\nv<sub>1</sub> = (2gh)<sup>1/2</sup>\n\n<u>Stokes Law</u>\nThe frictional force — also called drag force — exerted on spherical objects with very small Reynolds numbers (e.g., very small particles) in a continuous viscous fluid.\nF<sub>d</sub> = 6πηRV\nwhere η is the viscosity of the fluid in (in [kg m<sup>-1</sup> s<sup>-1</sup>]), R is the radius of the spherical object and V is the particle\'s velocity.\n\n<u>Reynolds Number</u>\nOsborne Reynolds (1842-1912) observed that turbulent flow is less likely for viscous fluid flowing at low rates. He defined a dimensionless number, whose value gives one an approximate idea whether the flow would be turbulent. This number is called the Reynolds R<sub>e</sub>\nR<sub>e</sub> = ρvd/η</string>
</resources>
